Falco? Where are you headed this late?
I forgot something at HQ,
so I'm going back to get it.
See you later!
Falco, could you do me a favor?
What's that, Mr. Kruger?
I want to send a letter, but...
...if it's sent from the internment zone,
they'll check it.
That's right.
They might find out I'm not really sick,
so could you send it from outside?
Sure thing. Is it to your family?
Yeah. I wanna tell 'em I'm here
and doing just fine.
"From One Hand to Another"
Hey, why all the commotion?
The whole Tybur family has come to visit!
Excuse me?
It's the Tyburs' personal guard.
They're not part of our military.
Come in.
Sorry to drop in on you.
I'm Willy, the head of the Tybur family.
Commander of the Warrior unit, Theo Magath.
It's an honor to meet you, Lord Tybur.
Nice to meet you, Commander Magath.
Allow me to introduce you to the family.
Having managed the Warrior unit
from the outset,
are you able to tell which of us
is the War Hammer Titan?
No, I haven't a clue.
One might wonder if it's even here at all.
You're very astute, just like I've heard.
But it's here.
The War Hammer Titan is among us.
I came here to see the statue of Helos.
A century ago, a mere human
slayed the devil of all earth
and became the renowned Marleyan
hero who saved the world--Helos.
How marvelous. So brave and
beautiful, with not a scratch.
Truly, the spirit of Marley.
The spirit, indeed.
For within, it's empty inside.
You're a tough critic, Commander.
I hear you're working to reinstate
Marleyan conscription?
War, for Marleyans,
exists solely inside their newspapers.
They're content to just read
about our lands expanding.
If our tamed devils or conquered armies
are eating the bullets, all the better.
One hopes letting Marleyans hear the
sound of bullets whizzing by their ears
will be enough to stop our
self-destructive march towards war.
If someone controlled Marley
from the shadows, I'd tell them:
It's already too late.
You truly don't hold back,
Commander. What can I say?
As you noted, this nation is
controlled by the Tyburs.
But this path of warmongering
was one that Marley chose on its own.
We gave Marley both freedom
and power in hopes of atonement.
But in the end, Eldia and Marley
were thrown into darkness.
The Tyburs are responsible for that.
I intend to reveal the truth to the world
at the upcoming festival.
My coming to see the statue was no lie.
Marley is in need of a hero once more.
Theo Magath... Will you not join hands with me?
Huh?
Morning, Pock!
Pieck! What are you doing?!
This way's more natural to me. Did I scare you?
Can you just walk upright?
Titans come from the south.
The wall will be less defended the closer
you get to these mountains up north.
Then, we should attack from the north?
That's one option.
However, the wharf is the only place
where our large ships can dock.
We could press our advantage.
So, the south?
But the south is where
our scout ships were lost.
It's where they're most focused.
The wharf might even be destroyed.
So, what are you trying to say?
I'm merely trying to share
the information I gathered.
All right, enough.
It was dumb to let an Eldian talk.
The Paradis Island planning is going just swell.
The brass in charge is oh so intelligent.
Can't wait to hear what they come up with.
Like entrusting the whole thing to four kids?
Hmm?
He's ahead. Falco passed up Gabi!
Look at 'em celebrate one little win.
Jeez. They've got no idea.
No matter how well Falco does
at this point, he'll never surpass Gabi.
Did you see him take off at the end?!
Hey, runts. What's the big deal?
Falco finally beat Gabi!
In grades?! Really?!
No, just in a race!
This is a historic feat!
Can you cut it out? You're embarrassing me.
That's pretty awesome!
Maybe you'll be the next Armor!
Ow!
It's way too late to compete against me!
I made our motherland proud in the war!
I know.
But they still haven't announced
a successor yet.
Until then, I'll do everything I can.
Man, talk about showing off.
Your brother's already inheriting the Beast!
You'll be an Honorary Marleyan!
What's the point of trying so hard?!
I'm doing it for you!
Whoa...
He totally said it!
Huh?! You're getting in my way,
but you're doing it for me?
That doesn't make any damn sense!
Guess it didn't get through.
Huh?! What's his problem?! What gives?!
Oh! Welcome back, our little Warriors!
Gabi! I heard what you did, Gabi!
You're our savior, Gabi!
Well, I'm Zofia, so...
Huh?
What's wrong with you?! Quit day drinking
and grabbing girls, you geezer!
Shuddap, you nincompoop!
What's wrong with praising a hero?!
If anything, being praised by you is bad luck!
Go on! Stumble back home to your mom!
Now then, I've got a treat for you kids!
Eat up and grow big like Vice Chief Braun!
Thank you!
Whoa!
Will they really declare war
right here in the zone?
Reminds me of a theater.
I heard they're inviting VIPs here
and after doing this festival,
the world will be on our side.
Fantastic!
All of Marley's problems will magically go away!
You think it won't work?
You actually do?
The Mid-East Forces we were
just slaughtering will be there.
My family came from an internment zone
abroad, so I know how awful it is.
The hate for Eldians abroad
makes here seem like nothing.
Well, all the more reason
we've gotta try something.
They might've chosen to hold it here
so people understand us!
We can show 'em we're not devils!
But how?
Smile!
I know you can't wait to show the world
they're wrong, but stop looking so smug.
And, Zofia... Cut it out with your weird act.
Um, this is who I am...
Fine! So what are you gonna fix?!
Huh? There's no need, 'cuz I'm perfect as-is!
I'm smart and cute as a button!
And when I captivate all the VIPs,
it'll secure my spot even more!
I think I spot a devil.
If you guys cheer for Falco again,
I'll make you cry!
You really are a devil!
It's Commander Magath.
Here.
Oh? A large-scale demolition is required?
It has decayed beyond repair.
Congratulations, General. The military is yours.
No. The military serves the nation,
and this nation's supreme commander is you.
That's not quite true.
I'm simply the one who holds the wheel.
Now I know why my
predecessors never tried to grab it.
It's so heavy.
I wish I could let go this very moment,
but a time has come where I must not.
It just happened to be me.
I'm simply the man
this responsibility fell upon.
The house was in danger of collapsing,
but some pillars remained usable.
According to them, the house
is already infested with rats.
Nice work, Falco.
It's all thanks to you, Kruger!
But at this point, I honestly doubt
I can pass up Gabi.
Even so, I'm gonna keep moving forward.
I see. I'm the one who should be
thanking you, though.
I'm grateful you've been sending
all my letters. You've been a big help.
Yeah...
Did your family send you that?
They thought it'd make
hospital life less boring.
Hard to do much in this shape, though.
I need to move forward, too.
When the festival's over,
I'm going back to my hometown.
I see.
A doctor's coming.
I'll get going!
Yeah.
May I sit next to you?
Yeah, sure.
I appreciate it.
I'm Jaeger, a physician for the zone.
I come here to drink tea sometimes.
Nice to meet you. I'm Kruger.
Nice to meet you, Kruger.
You seem to get along with that boy.
Yeah.
I see. I think I could get along with him, too.
I sit here on this bench looking
for people to talk to.
His uncle was a leader of
the Eldian Restorationists.
Restorationists are sent to paradise
and not even their family is spared.
To protect their family,
he and his brother trained to be Warriors,
and when his brother was chosen
to inherit the Beast Titan,
the Grice family knew they were finally safe.
Why are you telling me this?
Stop asking the boy to do favors for you.
If he comes under suspicion, all their
effort will have been for nothing.
And if you're truly healthy,
you should go back to your family.
Someday, you won't see them anymore.
Don't wait and live with regret.
Regret, huh?
You have regrets about your own family?
There's not a day that I don't.
That day, my son took
my daughter outside the walls.
It's because I was too strict
about him becoming a doctor!
It's my fault! Everything was my fault!
Mr. Jaeger! Please don't go around on your own!
I'm so sorry. I looked away for a second.
This way, Mr. Jaeger.
Everything will be okay.
"The Tybur Family joined hands with the Marleyan
hero Helos to overcome the Eldian Empire
and bring an end to the Great Titan War.
They have long possessed the War Hammer Titan."
Whoa!
I've seen them in the paper!
Cut the chitchat.
We've gotta be waiters like we trained.
Look, there's empty glasses! Get 'em!
--Falco, drink!
--Here!
Hmm? Oh... There's filthy blood
touching the plates.
Ugh! That explains why the food stinks!
I-I'm terribly sorry!
Shh! Don't make a fuss.
B-But your fancy clothes--!
Is everything all right, madam?
How embarrassing!
I spilled wine on my kimono
and was asking for help!
Thank you.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Please, come this way.
Wh-Why?
Who knows what would've happened to you.
You okay?
Yeah... She saved me.
She knew I was an Eldian.
That woman... I think she's
an Easterner from Hizuru.
It's Willy!
Willy! Kin of our saviors!
Ambassador Ogweno! Long time no see!
Nambia! We were kids last time I saw you!
I used to make you cry all the time!
Remember this, Willy?
Oh! From the time you fell out of the tree!
Ladies and Gentlemen!
We thank you all for coming tonight!
Until recently, we were squabbling
over resources in an unsightly war.
However, yesterday's enemy is today's enemy!
Pardon me. Yesterday's enemy is today's friend!
Let's wash the past
down the toilet with our drinks!
Please raise your glasses
and join me for a toast!
To everlasting peace!
Thank you very much! Such an elegant
joke to amuse our guests!
--Huh?
--But I'm afraid our guests
didn't quite understand,
so allow me to take over.
Yeah, Willy!
Kin of our saviors!
Tomorrow, I invite all of you
to the Liberio Internment Zone.
It is the home of a people
whose blood runs through me.
The ones called devils for slaughtering
a great number of people--the Eldians.
Though once repressed more greatly than any,
Marley has used the devils to oppress
other nations and repeat the tragedy.
I understand the desire
to exterminate the Eldians.
But I have arrived at a single solution
that will answer this endless problem.
Tomorrow, I will reveal that solution
in my first-ever theater production.
To the great playwrights
and witnesses of history!
To the playwrights and witnesses of history!
What the--?!
What in the world?!
Gabi! You're finally up!
What's happening?!
The festival!
People from outside came pouring in
and opened all these stalls!
Try this!
This is a festival?!
Let's go!
It hurts!
'Cuz you stuffed your face.
I wish we had festivals every day! Blech!
Yeah.
Lately, it seems like lots of new
things have been happening.
It does.
It kinda feels like something
is about to change!
Yeah.
It does.
Oh? Did you guys have fun?
Huh? Where's Falco?
He said he saw someone he knew and ran off.
Really? What's the matter with him?
Can't you just loosen up for a day?
So many people...
Huh? Looks like he's back.
Mr. Braun!
Where the hell did you go?
Can you come with me?
Right now?
You'll be fine. It shouldn't start for a bit.
This way!
What's this all about?
You'll see soon enough!
In here!
Okay.
I brought him!
Hey. It's been four years, Reiner.
Eren!
In a dusky cellar, Reiner confronts Eren.
As the crowd is absorbed
by Willy's speech, Eren admits:
"I'm the same as you."
Next episode: "Declaration of War."